

■ Nathan.A.Irvin@gmail.com

https://irv0735.github.io/Nate-Irvin-Portfolio/

in https://www.linkedin.com/in/irvinnathan/ O irv0735

EDUCATION

SUMMARY

June 2021 University of Denver to Dec. Certificate Full-Stack 2021 Coding Bootcamp

24 week intensive Web Development training

Aug. Purdue University

2007 to B.S. Electrical

May 2012 Engineering

Minor - Management

Problem solving is in my DNA and I have applied that to all facets of my life and career. You'll consistently find me pursuing a solution to a complex problem or researching new tools and languages that may provide more elegant solutions in the future.

SKILLS

LANGUAGES: JavaScript (ES6), HTML5, CSS3, GraphQL, Python

TECHNOLOGIES: React.js, Node, Express, MySQL, MongoDB, Sequelize, Mongoose, Apollo, Handlebars.js, AWS

TOOLS/METHODS: Git, Heroku, Agile, SCRUM

SOFT SKILLS: Problem Solving, Strategic Thinking, Priotization, Interpersonal, Product Development, Risk Management, Process Improvement

EMPLOYMENT

BORDER STATES

Rocky Mountain Region
Utility Application Specialist

Oct. 2017 to Current

Manage and facilitate the sales and support of smart metering, grid edge intelligence and smart infrastructure technologies to electric, gas and water utilities

LANDIS+GYR TECHNOLOGIES

Product Manager - Commercial and Industrial Metering

Manage the full life cycle of the C&I metrology and communication solutions - both hardware and embedded software components

Senior Product Specialist

Handled regulatory approvals, 3rd party integration projects and meter development projects under sustaining efforts

Electronics Engineer

Hardware focused design, testing and failure analysis

Lafayette, IN June 2014 to Aug. 2016

Aug. 2016 to Sept. 2017

Lafayette, IN

Lafayette, IN Jan. 2012 to June 2014

PROJECTS

FRIENDS OF TOTO Nov. 2021 to Dec. 2021

Built web app using React and Material UI component library Utilized global context for state management with actions/reducers

Utilized bcrypt hashing and JWT for signing/verifying session tokens

Utilized Apollo client to interface with the GraphQL API

Interfaced with AWS S3 Bucket for image/post uploads by the users

OUROBOROS Sept. 2021 to Oct. 2021

Built Node/Express app following the MVC design pattern with a mySQL database

Built secure user authentication utilizing bcrypt hashing and sessions

Utilized handlebars.js for templating engine

Constructed REST APIs to interface with the database

Interfaced with AWS S3 Bucket for user profile image upload/storage

RSN FINANCIAL July 2021 to Aug. 2021

Built web app with HTML5, CSS3, jQuery, and vanilla JavaScript

Utilized Foundation styling framework along with Google Font CDN

Utilized browser localStorage to preserve the user's stock watch list

Created custom script to integrate multiple 3rd Party APIs for stock content and currency exchange

WEATHER APP July 2021 to July 2021

Built web app in 3 days using raw HTML5, CSS3, and vanilla JavaScript

Utilized Flexbox and pure CSS for styling

Created custom script to interface with OpenWeather's API to derive weather in searched locations

Utilized localStorage to preserve the search history